Finding Aid for the Robert Drake Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Robert Drake Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0117
32.50 linear_feet
- Correspondences, 1959-1995
  - 1959-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1980 -1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - January 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - February 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - March 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - April 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - May 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - June 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - July 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - August 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - September 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - October 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - November 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - December 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - January 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - February 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - March 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - April 1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - May 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - June 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - July 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - August 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - September 1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - October 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - November 1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - December 1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - January 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - February 1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - March 1995 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - August 1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - September 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - October 1995 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - November 1995 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - December 1995 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Correspondence 1996-1999
  - January 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - February 1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - March 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - April 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - May 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - June 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - July 1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - August 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - September 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - October 1996 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - November 1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - December 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - January 1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - February 1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - March 1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - April 1997 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - May 1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - June 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - July 1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - August 1997 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - September 1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - October 1997 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - November 1997 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - December 1997 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1998 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Short Stories (1)
  - The Methodist Church, the Democratic party and the St. Louis Cardinals (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stardust (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - The Cotton Mill (Box 3)
    - The Old Cemetery (Box 3)
  - Alone (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Last Lady on the Epilogue (Box 3)
    - Shrouds with Pockets in Them (Box 3)
    - How Come You Reckon He Did That? (Box 3)
  - Travelling Companions (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - The Last of the Innocents (Box 3)
    - All Under One Roof (Box 3)
    - The Girls (Box 3)
  - A Short Horse (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Let There be Light (Box 3)
    - The Devil, Lightning and Policemen (Box 3)
    - Gallery Talk (Box 3)
  - I’ve got a Sneaking Idea (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The convertible (Box 3)
    - Little Girls with Blue Eyes (Box 3)
    - The Last Old Maid in Town (Box 3)
  - Graduation from the Air (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Piazza (Box 3)
    - The Election (Box 3)
    - Every Friday Afternoon (Box 3)
  - What Will you do for an Encore? (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Home Place (Box 3)
    - Introduction for Relief (Box 3)
    - An English Hidalgo (Box 3)
  - Miss Welty’s Country and My Own (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Is Regionalism a Bad Word? (Box 3)
    - Review of Southern Writers at Century’s End (Box 3)
  - Southern Writers at Centuries End (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Partisan, 1997 (Box 3)
  - The Observer, the Outsider (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Robert Drake’s North South Axis (Box 3)
    - Good and Faithful Servant (Box 3)
    - Southern Partisan (Box 3)
  - Long Long Thoughts (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Tell Him to Wait till I get My Shoes On (Box 3)
    - Tara Forty Years After (Box 3)
    - The Holocaust and the Literary Imagination (Box 3)
  - My Stories; Short on Length, Long on Talk (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - The Old Lady Power (Box 3)
    - Flannery O’Connor an American Literature (Box 3)
    - Acknowledgements (Box 3)
  - The Writers Dreams (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Composition and Rhetoric and the Warders of the Gate (Box 3)
    - In Time and Place (Box 3)
    - In and Out of Yoknapatawpha (Box 3)
  - Allen Tate (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Son of the Morning (Box 3)
    - Miss Welty’s Country and my Own (Box 3)
    - Writing and Listening (Box 3)
  - The Wonderful Nows (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Three Southern Ladies (Box 3)
    - Unsearchable Riches (Box 3)
    - The Legacy of Allen Tate (Box 3)
  - The Perils of Internship (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Hemingway and Faulkner (Box 3)
    - Southern Women (Box 3)
    - The Lone Eagle and the American Dream (Box 3)
  - The Big Wide World of Ripley, Tennessee (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - The Glory that is Greece (Box 3)
    - The Dreadful Past the Blessed Past (Box 3)
    - Our Old Home (Box 3)
  - Cranks, Nuts and Gizzards (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - The Uses of Obscenity (Box 3)
    - My Novel (Box 3)
    - America Prophecies, Dreams, Visions (Box 3)
  - Taking Stock (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - South the Towers Rising (Box 3)
    - The Performer (Box 3)
    - My Affair with Eustace Tilley (Box 3)
  - The Carter Prospect (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - The Wonders at the Gate (Box 3)
    - The Emperor’s Clothes (Box 3)
    - Getting Above Your Rising (Box 3)
  - Games Authors Play (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Good Behavior (Box 3)
    - My Christmas Journey (Box 3)
    - Why I Write Fiction (Box 3)
  - The Home Place (1) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - The Home Place (2) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The Home Place (3) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Home Place (4) (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Short Stories (2)
  - The Observer, the Outsider (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Little Girl with Blue Eyes (short stories) (Box 4)
  - The Blue Remembered Hills of Lauderdale County, Tennessee (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Writer and the Corridors of Memory (Box 4)
    - Teaching Fiction Writing (Box 4)
  - The Writer as Hunger Artist (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - The Writer (Box 4)
    - Writers and History (Box 4)
  - All Your Children will be Born Naked (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - The Loving Vision (Box 4)
    - The Wood Landers (Box 4)
    - The Lonely Heart of Carson McCullers (Box 4)
  - Practice Music (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Austin Warren (1899-1986) (Box 4)
    - Morning Song (Box 4)
  - What Papa Said (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The Enormous Spider Web of Robert Penn Warren (Box 4)
    - Practice Music Practice Music (Box 4)
    - Memphis for the Day (Box 4)
  - Thoreau and Mrs. Hamby (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Over the Mountains (Box 4)
    - New Year’s Eve (Box 4)
  - Tara Twenty Years After (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Richard Marias (Box 4)
    - An Audience with Mr. Faulkner (Box 4)
    - The Living Room (Box 4)
  - Do you Know Ben Webster (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - I Don’t Know What He is Doing Now (Box 4)
    - The Art of Fiction (Box 4)
    - The Nigger of the Narcissus (Box 4)
  - The Little Jewish Lady (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - What Were You Doing When You Heard the News? (Box 4)
    - Auntie’s Message (Box 4)
    - Good and Faithful Servant (Box 4)
  - The Lady From Somewhere (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Miss Welty’s Country and My Own (Box 4)
    - Regionalism in American Fiction (Box 4)
    - Hemingway and Faulkner (Box 4)
  - The Sauce for the Asparagus (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Miss Minerva and William Green Hill (Box 4)
  - Absalom, Absalom or Why Southerners Tell Stories (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Two Eudora Welty Stories (Box 4)
    - Saki’s Ironic Stories (Box 4)
    - Manners Anyone? Or Who Killed the Butler? (Box 4)
  - Gentlemen, Blondes & Brunettes (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Signs of the Times, or Signs of all Times (Box 4)
    - Greatness Through Limitation (Box 4)
    - Flannery O’Connor and American Culture (Box 4)
  - The Paradigm of Flannery O’Connor’s True County (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Three Southern Ladies (Box 4)
    - The Bleeding Stinking Mad Shadow of Jesus (Box 4)
    - The Reasons of the Heart (Box 4)
  - Yoknapatawpha Innocence Lost (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - As the Old as Man Himself (Box 4)
  - The Modern Inferno (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - A Joyful Noise (Box 4)
    - The Lady Old Power (Box 4)
  - Mother, Father Three Sons (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Family of Fire (Box 4)
    - The Picture Frame and Other Stories (Box 4)
  - An Audience with Mr. Faulkner (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The Writer as Observer, the Writer as Outsider (Box 4)
    - Southern Writers at the Century’s End (Box 4)
  - A Sweet Touch (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - As Clean as the Ten Commandments (Box 4)
    - For the Prestige (Box 4)
    - New Year’s Eve (Box 4)
  - Over the Mountains (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The Maxwell girls (Box 4)
    - What Papa Said? (Box 4)
    - A Sweet Touch (Box 4)
  - Brutally Massacred by Indians (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Feeding the Stocks (Box 4)
    - The Living Room (Box 4)
    - What Have They Done? (Box 4)
  - Change of Life (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Raining Cotton (Box 4)
    - The Clothes Line (Box 4)
  - What Will I Do For an Encore? (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - The Square (Box 4)
    - Luella and Mr. Kelly (Box 4)
  - Frances Newsman: Fabulist of Decadence (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - The Last of the Innocents (Box 4)
    - Aloodiceqan: A Note on a Minor Novel (Box 4)
  - The Cea Critic (October,1969) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - The Drake Interview (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Short Stories (3)
  - The First Year (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - On the Side Porch (Box 5)
    - The Clothes Line (Box 5)
  - Graduation from the Air (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - The Last Old Maid in Town (Box 5)
  - The High World (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - All this Material (Box 5)
    - The Piazza (Box 5)
  - Assorted Stories (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Dark Angel in My Life (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Home Truths (Box 5)
    - Time Place and the Past (Box 5)
    - The New Bridge (Box 5)
  - A Splendid Summer (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Happy Warrior Goes Home (Box 5)
    - One World at a Time (Box 5)
    - Flannery O’Conner, 1978 (Box 5)
  - A Church for all Seasons (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Professor, what do you Profess? (Box 5)
    - Miss Minerva Again (Box 5)
    - I Never Write Letters (Box 5)
  - I’ve Got a Sneaking Idea (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Star Dust (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - A Short Horse (Box 5)
  - What do You do Now (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Comedy of Manners (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - The Day (Box 5)
    - Alone (Box 5)
  - Robert Penn Warren (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Nigger of the Narcissus (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Comedy of Manners (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Why Southerners Tell Stories (Box 5)
  - Teaching Fiction Writing (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - The Train in My Life (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The Dream House (Box 5)
  - William Faulkner: Toward Yoknapatawpha and Beyond (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - In Time and Place: Some Origins of America Fiction (Box 5)
    - Robert Coles, Flannery O’Connor’s South. (Box 5)
  - Donald Davidson and the Ancient Mariner (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - My Christmas Journey (Box 5)
    - The Legacy of Allen Tate (Box 5)
    - Southern Women (Box 5)
  - Dutch Genre Painter (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - The Writer as Listener (Box 5)
    - I Can Tell You All About It (Box 5)
  - Southern Women: Fact and Fiction. (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Short Stories (4)
  - The Home Place: A Memory and a Celebration (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Single Heart (script) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Robert Drake reviews (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Comic Monologues: Robert Drake’s Community of Voices (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Picture Frame and Other Stories (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - For the Record (Final Draft) I (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - For the Record (Final Draft) II (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - For the Record (Final Draft) III (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - For the Record (Final Draft) IV (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - For the Record (Final Draft) V (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Telling and Reckoning: A Recuperation of the Drake Stories. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The Interpretation of Otherness (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Home truths. Heart truths (Box 6)
    - Pietas Medici (Box 6)
    - A Dutch Genre Painter (Box 6)
  - The Big Room (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Flannery O’Connor’s South (Box 6)
    - My Country, My Voices (Box 6)
    - Violence and Culture in the Antebellum South (Box 6)
  - I Don’t Want You to Ever Call Again (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - The Loving Vision of Eudora Welty (Box 6)
    - The Scalpel and the Pen (Box 6)
    - Going Home (Box 6)
  - Modern Age (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Why Flannery O’Connor Stayed Home (Box 6)
    - All Your Children Will Be Born Naked (Box 6)
    - Lamar Alexander, Robin Hood, and Barry Parker (Box 6)
  - Survivors (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - I Can Tell You All About It (Box 6)
    - A Joyful Noise (Box 6)
    - Tell Me a Story (Box 6)
  - The Writer: Behind the Scenes (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - She Won’t Cook (Box 6)
    - Is There Any Market for Good Women? (Box 6)
  - Morning Song (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - The Lady from Somewhere (Box 6)
    - One Writer’s Pieties (Box 6)
  - The Little Boy and His Bank (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Why Southerners Tell Stories (Box 6)
    - The Writer as Hunger Artist (Box 6)
    - Good Evening Ladies and Gentlemen (Box 6)
  - Let There Be Light (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - William Hall Drake and His Family (Box 6)
    - Risen Sun (Box 6)
    - Talk of Stewardship (Box 6)
- Short Stories (5)
  - No More Use Than a Billy Goat (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - It’s So Close in Here (Box 7)
    - A Dead Cat on the Line (Box 7)
  - A Short Horse (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - A Note on the Text (Box 7)
    - We are going to Mark Things Down (Box 7)
    - A Gentle Quarrel with Readers (Box 7)
  - A Short Horse (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Cultivating My Antique Garden (Box 7)
    - The Last of the Innocents (Box 7)
    - Miss O’Connor and the Scandal of Redemption (Box 7)
  - New Year’s Eve (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Ceremonies (Box 7)
    - Austin Warren (1899-1986) (Box 7)
    - The Little Jewish Lady (Box 7)
  - The Lady from Somewhere (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Miss Effie the Peabody and the Father Time (Box 7)
    - Mrs. Picture Show Green (Box 7)
    - The writer as the hunger artist (Box 7)
  - My sweet hearts house (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - The first year (Box 7)
    - Douglas Pascal (Box 7)
    - The birth day picture (Box 7)
  - His heart his home (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - The Methodist church, the Democratic Party and the St. Louis cardinals (Box 7)
    - Christianity and literature (Box 7)
  - A back bedroom an open fire and the art of fiction (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Code interview (Box 7)
    - She won’t cook (Box 7)
    - Red warren: His heart his home (Box 7)
  - The writer as the hunger artist (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Notre dame magazine, 1998 (Box 7)
    - Dedication and preface (Box 7)
  - The Maxwell girls (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Them fried niggers smell good don’t they clover? (Box 7)
    - Counting out (Box 7)
    - Daddy and the preachers (Box 7)
  - Austin warren (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Cleanth brooks (Box 7)
    - Daddy and the devil (Box 7)
    - Travelling companions (Box 7)
  - Speeches (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The picture frame and other stories (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The lunch box (Box 7)
  - Writing in the southern traditional interviews with southern contemporary authors (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - The picture frame (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Every Friday afternoon (Box 7)
    - The last of the innocents (Box 7)
  - The beauty revue counting out (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Tight fisted till the end (Box 7)
  - The legitimate pleasures of literature (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Short Stories VI
  - Connections (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Let there be light (Box 8)
  - The day (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The devil, lightning and policemen (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - All under the roof (Box 8)
  - The cotton mill (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The old cemetery (Box 8)
  - The little girl with blue eyes (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Travelling companions (Box 8)
  - Star dust (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - I’ve got a sneaking idea (Box 8)
  - The convertible (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The pickup truck (Box 8)
  - The two nieces (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Graduation from the air (Box 8)
  - The girls (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Every Friday after noon (Box 8)
  - How come you recon he did that (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - The last old maid in town (Box 8)
  - A short horse (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Shrouds with pockets in them (Box 8)
  - The Peabody ducks and all the rest (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - All that believe that, stand on their head (Box 8)
  - For the record (script) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Reading Robert drake (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - The election (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - The child prodigy (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Alone (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - For the record I (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - For the record II (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Hearing voices of women at the back of my mind (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - The Whig in the Robert drake fiction (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Telling and reckoning (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - A sort of central fact about Woodsville (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - A rail road as a metaphor in the works of Robert drake (Box 8)
  - A southern realist (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Family of five (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - The Whig ethos in Robert drake fiction (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Hearing the voices of women at the back of my mind (Box 8)
  - For the record (final draft) I (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - For the record (final draft) II (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - For the record (final draft) III (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - For the record (final draft) IV (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - The single heart (Box 8, Folder 31)
- short stories VII
  - What do we do now (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - At the lake (Box 9)
    - All this material and other such things (Box 9)
    - The picture frame (Box 9)
  - Connections (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - The pickup truck (Box 9)
    - For the prestige (Box 9)
    - The child prodigy (Box 9)
  - How come the Maxell girls (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - All this material (Box 9)
    - Let there be light (Box 9)
  - The last old maid in town (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Cleanth Brooks (Box 9)
    - What papa said? (Box 9)
    - Auntie ant the two nieces (Box 9)
  - Eve of St. Agnes (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - The kingdom of God in marigold Mississippi (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Uncle john and the trail of the years (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Mr. Andrew and the big holly tree (Box 9)
    - Easy steps for little feet (Box 9)
  - Mrs. Higgins heart (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Daddy and the bull and the bull named Herbert (Box 9)
    - The moss girls (Box 9)
    - Saki’s ironic stories (Box 9)
  - The summer of the widow peeper (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Manners anyone (Box 9)
    - The fountain filled with blood (Box 9)
    - By thy good pleasure (Box 9)
  - The stark naked Baptist (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - A lacodician (Box 9)
    - Mr. Marcus and the overhead bridge (Box 9)
    - By thy good pleasure (Box 9)
  - The hair curling gospel (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Manners anyone (Box 9)
    - A modern inferno (Box 9)
    - The bridegroom cometh (Box 9)
  - Mr. Davison and the ancient mariner (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Dear dead Hollywood (Box 9)
    - Huck among the doctors (Box 9)
  - Huck among the doctors (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - The time the bank failed (Box 9)
    - The first funeral (Box 9)
    - The nine year old evangelist (Box 9)
  - The home place I (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - The home place II (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - The home place III (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - The home place IV (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Mr. Wood Wad and the past (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Lorelei Dorothy and the comedy of manners (Box 9)
    - The woodlands and the traditional pastoral (Box 9)
    - By thy good pleasure (Box 9)
  - Miss O’Connor and the scandal of redemption (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Flannery O’Conner RIP (Box 9)
    - The fall of man and the puritan mind (Box 9)
    - The bowel fearful people (Box 9)
  - Mrs. Piccard and the Baptists (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Some problems and a biography (Box 9)
  - The last of the innocents (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - An audience with Mr. Faulkner a centennial Memoir (Box 9)
    - The writer as hunger artist (Box 9)
    - The writer as observer, the writer as insider (Box 9)
  - The last of the innocents (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Tara twenty years after (Box 9)
    - The book the movie the dream (Box 9)
    - Robert Drake’s north south axis (Box 9)
  - All under one roof (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Ella Biggs (Box 9)
    - I am counting with you all the way (Box 9)
    - Why southerners tell stories (Box 9)
- Short Stories VIII
  - The single heart (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Amazing grace (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Short Stories IX
  - For the record (1) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - For the record (2) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - For the record (3) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - For the record (4) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Survivors and others (original copy) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Robert drake story collection (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The home place a memory and a celebration. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Reviews, Publications and Personal Documents.
  - The southern review (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Christianity and literature (Autumn 1996) (Box 12)
    - September 1987 Publications (Box 12)
  - The Chattahoochee review Vol. XVI (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Robert Drake reviews I (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Robert Drake reviews II (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Robert Drake reviews III (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Robert Drake reviews IV (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Publications, 1953-1999 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - My literary equipment (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Critics to Robert’s work (Box 12)
  - Mississippi quarterly, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Mississippi quarterly, 1994-1997 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Bridgton press, 2014 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Robert Drake CV (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Speaking engagements, (1965-1995) (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Drake interview (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Graduate student hand book (Box 12, Folder 15)